#### Joel Diaz

347-698-7452 | joeldiazjdv@gmail.com

GitHub: joeljdv | Blog | LinkedIn

### **QUALIFICATION SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with emphasis on Ruby on Rails and JavaScript with over 525 hours of classroom and lab experience. A self-motivated analytical person that excels under pressure and can work independently or on a team. Bilingual both written and verbal in English and Spanish.

Collaborator

Customer Service

Creative

Active Listener

Communication

Time Management

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby

**JavaScript** 

SOL

Ruby on Rails

React

HTML & CSS

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

# Breakout Game | GitHub: https://github.com/joeljdv/breakout-game

This app is a breakout game, the objective of the game is to break all the blocks on the screen without losing all five lives.

- Used HTML and CSS to render the grid, add colors, and position all the elements.
- Used JavaScript to create blocks, start the game, and move the paddle.
- Used the x and y coordinates of the ball, the paddle, and the blocks to know the position of each.

## Blog | GitHub: https://github.com/joeljdv/posts-app

This app is a blog, where a user can log in and create a post, see the posts made by other users, and interact with them by making comments.

- Used Ruby on Rails to create an API to store all the user's data (user info, posts, comments)
- Used React for the front end. Utilized hooks to locally store the data necessary, like the user's information to render a profile page.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Domino's Pizza Queens, New York 09/2018 - 08/2021

**Delivery Expert** 

Responsible for food delivery

- Customer Service including both on the phone and in-person.
- Organize and clean the store before opening and after closing.

**Delta Airlines** Queens, New York 11/2021 - Present Ramp Agent

- Responsible for making sure gates are clear for incoming planes.
- Manage all incoming and outgoing baggage.
- Continuous communication with our team to make sure all safety protocols are in place.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Online/Remote Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 03/2021-08/2021